
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <channel>
   <title>challenge on Brain storage</title>
   <link>https://ivgivanov.info/tags/challenge/</link>
   <description>Recent content in challenge on Brain storage</description>
   <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 12:26:42 +0200</lastBuildDate>
   
       <atom:link href="https://ivgivanov.info/tags/challenge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
   
     <item>
       <title>VMware vCenter tasks and events collection</title>
       <link>https://ivgivanov.info/posts/vcenter-tasks-events-collectors/</link>
       <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 15:23:22 +0200</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://ivgivanov.info/posts/vcenter-tasks-events-collectors/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;vCenter tasks and events provide valuable information that can be used for historical and audit purposes. They are stored in the vCenter Server&amp;rsquo;s database and available until the data retention setting is reached. By default tasks and events are cleaned up after 30 days and increasing this limit can result in a significant increase of the vCenter Server&amp;rsquo;s DB size. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to share my experience with getting this data programmatically for use in a 3rd party software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;choosing-which-api-to-use&#34;&gt;Choosing which API to use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was involved in a project where vCenter tasks and events had to be collected with a Java client. Additionally, the required backward compatibility and presence of existing integration left no room for anything else but the vSphere Web Services API. In my opinion, it takes an effort to get used to it. It&amp;rsquo;s quite abstract (probably for a good reason) and you really need to get your hands dirty to start getting familiar with it. But let&amp;rsquo;s get to the point, using the vSphere Web Services API to get tasks and events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-managers&#34;&gt;The Managers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, there are 2 &amp;ldquo;Managed Object&amp;rdquo; (to use VMware&amp;rsquo;s dictionary) that are perfect for the job:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vdc-repo.vmware.com/vmwb-repository/dcr-public/c476b64b-c93c-4b21-9d76-be14da0148f9/04ca12ad-59b9-4e1c-8232-fd3d4276e52c/SDK/vsphere-ws/docs/ReferenceGuide/vim.TaskManager.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;TaskManager&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://vdc-repo.vmware.com/vmwb-repository/dcr-public/c476b64b-c93c-4b21-9d76-be14da0148f9/04ca12ad-59b9-4e1c-8232-fd3d4276e52c/SDK/vsphere-ws/docs/ReferenceGuide/vim.event.EventManager.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;EventManager&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentation is quite good and you can get the expected results pretty fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tip: If you have access to vCenter Server you can navigate to https://vc-address/mob, authenticate and navigate to the desired Managed Object type where you can execute methods and see results directly in the browser. For example https://vc-address/mob/?moid=TaskManager&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;limitations&#34;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything was going just fine until we started testing - data for some objects were missing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little back story, in this case, the collection was happening per object, as this was the best way to tie it to the rest of the application flow. Ok, moving on. Of course, there was an error logged:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;com.vmware.vim25.InvalidStateFaultMsg: The operation is not allowed in the current state.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I saw it first I pretty much ignored it, as I knew there were some hosts in &lt;em&gt;Not Connected&lt;/em&gt; state and I figured this was the cause. Later, after the missing data was obvious, I started to doubt my initial opinion, because it didn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense - the tasks and events are provided by the vCenter Server and reside on its database. The object state shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have any influence on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer was in another useful documentation &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.vmware.com/docs/17686/vsphere-web-services-sdk-programming-guide-8-0/GUID-DDFF7502-D9A6-4E55-AEA3-93D14E32AC67.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;vSphere Web Services SDK Programming Guide:&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;DestroyCollector – A HistoryCollector exists only for the current session. Invoke the DestroyCollector operation to explicitly destroy the collector before the session ends.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;CreateCollectorForTasks&lt;/code&gt; method of the &lt;em&gt;TaskManager&lt;/em&gt; (or its alternative in the &lt;em&gt;EventManager&lt;/em&gt;) creates a &lt;code&gt;TaskHistoryCollector&lt;/code&gt; but there is a limited number of those that can exist concurrently. The exact limit is &lt;em&gt;32&lt;/em&gt; as specified by the &lt;code&gt;maxCollector&lt;/code&gt; property of the &lt;em&gt;TaskManager&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;EventManager&lt;/em&gt;. In the scope of the project, there was no need to continuously monitor the tasks of a given object, there for the collector could be safely destroyed once the initial collection is completed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implementing the use of &lt;code&gt;destroyCollector&lt;/code&gt; method helped to avoid reaching the &lt;code&gt;maxCollectors&lt;/code&gt; limit and effectively get all the data that was needed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>100 Days of Code - Challenge Completed!</title>
       <link>https://ivgivanov.info/posts/100-days-of-code-completed/</link>
       <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 12:26:42 +0200</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://ivgivanov.info/posts/100-days-of-code-completed/</guid>
       <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;day-100-of-100daysofcode&#34;&gt;Day &lt;strong&gt;100&lt;/strong&gt; of #100DaysOfCode&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a little hard to believe but &lt;strong&gt;I DID IT&lt;/strong&gt;! A hundred days, at least one hour per day working on my coding skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was it difficult to keep up? Sometimes yes.&lt;br&gt;
Besides normal things like having a bad day or not in a mood to code, during this challenge I had to handle other things like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my birthday (30 y.o.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my son&amp;rsquo;s birthday (4 y.o.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;family camping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;flying abroad just me and my son&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;being sick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But hey, that was very small portion of the whole challenge. Overall, I really liked it! The satisfaction of doings something you haven&amp;rsquo;t done before (and especially if it works) is really motivating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-approach&#34;&gt;My approach&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a full time job and a happy family with 4 year old kid at home. My free time is quite limited so I had to squeeze every possible minute. Mainly I was coding during the late evening, once my son goes to sleep. This often resulted in not much sleep and less time spend with my wife, but she was extremely supportive throughout this challenge (most of the time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was mixing theory (blogs, video lessons and tutorials) and practice. I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of &amp;ldquo;just practice&amp;rdquo; because for me is important to understand how something works, not just that I managed to google a solution and apply it. Sometimes, I could be stuck with a 2-hours video for days until I put all the things together in my mind and make sure I can apply whatever I&amp;rsquo;m learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last, but the most important one - find a mentor! I&amp;rsquo;m lucky to be working in a software company with great software engineers. The opportunity to talk to someone about what you do, at least to make sure you understand some complex concepts, is priceless. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know any devs so far don&amp;rsquo;t worry, the #100DaysOfCode community is very supportive and I&amp;rsquo;m sure many will offer you help if you just reach out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to cover all what I have planned (you can check my previous post). I wrote an app in 3 different ways, based on my Java knowledge I gained during the challenge. Very soon the last version will be publicly available to everyone (and hopefully useful).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to speak more about my experience during the VMware Code&amp;rsquo;s CodeConnect conference. More info at &lt;a href=&#34;https://vmwarecodeconnect.github.io/CodeConnect2020/Ivaylo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;CodeConect schedule&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will I do the challenge again? Probably not soon. Will I continue coding? Hell yeah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thank-you&#34;&gt;Thank you!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big thank you to the #100DaysOfCode community and many others who were supporting me on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ivgivanov&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
 during the challenge! You&amp;rsquo;re making a difference!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>100 Days of Code</title>
       <link>https://ivgivanov.info/posts/100-days-of-code/</link>
       <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 21:22:05 +0200</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://ivgivanov.info/posts/100-days-of-code/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;I was having the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.100daysofcode.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;100daysOfCode&lt;/a&gt;
 challenge page opened in my browser for about a month before I actually decided to start. It might be a late Sunday evening decision, but I feel finally ready to start this commitment! This is going to be totally new experience for me, but since it&amp;rsquo;s something I really want to do I think I&amp;rsquo;ll enjoy the ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consider myself privileged to already work in a software company. Even though I&amp;rsquo;m not a developer (&lt;em&gt;yet&lt;/em&gt;), in my current position I often act as a bridge between the development team and the technology our software works with. &lt;a href=&#34;https://runecast.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;Runecast Analyzer&lt;/a&gt;
 is a knowledge automation solution which does analysis of VMware infrastructure and AWS public cloud against known and documented issues, security profiles, best practices etc.&lt;br&gt;
I, as a VMware Engineer, often browse through the VMware SDK while defining specific requirements for the next piece of the puzzle we want to automate. With time, I started to look also more at the Java implementation which helps me be more productive while communicating with our awesome developers. Little by little my interest grew stronger and I decided it is time to take it to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goal&#34;&gt;Goal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My ultimate goal after completing this challenge is to be able to pass an interview for junior Java developer. I&amp;rsquo;m not looking into changing my job completely, instead I see this more like a milestone I want to achieve.&lt;br&gt;
The following should help me get there:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a habit to code more often&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn Spring framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand Maven&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to write more complex SQL queries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plan&#34;&gt;Plan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to leverage my current knowledge and expertise in the VMware domain and strengthen it with exploring how things actually work in the background.&lt;br&gt;
Along with that, I&amp;rsquo;ll start a Java programming course at &lt;a href=&#34;https://pluralsight.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;pluralsight&lt;/a&gt;
 where I have annual subscription as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://vexpert.vmware.com/directory/112&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;VMware vExpert&lt;/a&gt;
. And most importantly, practice, practice and practice!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be sending regular updates on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ivgivanov&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
 and when there is something more I want to say I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting it as a blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;connect&#34;&gt;Connect&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Already started following some people on twitter which are on different levels of this challenge. The community seems great and I&amp;rsquo;m glad to become a part of it.
I&amp;rsquo;m always happy to hear feedback or suggestions. If you have an advice you want to share or just want to chat, feel free to reach out via &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ivgivanov&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>About Me</title>
       <link>https://ivgivanov.info/posts/about-me/</link>
       <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 15:32:07 +0200</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://ivgivanov.info/posts/about-me/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Ivaylo [Ivo] Ivanov. I&amp;rsquo;m an IT oriented person working in server virtualization field. I&amp;rsquo;ve been breathing &lt;strong&gt;VMware&lt;/strong&gt; for the past 7 years, working with many products from their portfolio. Even though majority of my IT career was on the Ops/Engineering side, I always enjoy writing scripts. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s safe to say that I&amp;rsquo;m quite interested in programming, probably ever since I finished university (where actually this was may major, but somehow I tried to get around it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m extremely happy that since 2017 I joined &lt;a href=&#34;https://runecast.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Runecast&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&lt;/a&gt;
. A startup, founded by a group of crazy smart people and also amazing friends! This makes me part of a software company where I learned A LOT new stuff. Hell, I even have committed some (&lt;em&gt;simple&lt;/em&gt;) JAVA code which is running in production. On daily basis I&amp;rsquo;m taking care of the virtual infrastructure, exploring new technologies and helping developers to be more productive in every way I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things you can hear me say during my work time include, but not limited to: vmware, git, sdk, api, java, powershell, bash, jenkins, postgres, tomcat, jira, confluence, script, workflow, scrum, apt, ssh, &amp;ldquo;do you hear me now?&amp;rdquo; (while WFH).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Hello World</title>
       <link>https://ivgivanov.info/posts/hello-world/</link>
       <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 18:22:39 +0200</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://ivgivanov.info/posts/hello-world/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello World!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first post using Hugo and written only using the command line. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is actually being hosted completely for free using GitHub Pages. Of course, it supports custom domains, so basically if you have your own domain name you don&amp;rsquo;t even need to pay for and maintain hosting system. I&amp;rsquo;m still exploring Hugo, the themes and how to set up menus etc.
For upcoming posts I&amp;rsquo;ll probably switch to using VS Code with some markdown plugin. It should make it a bit easier to write and edit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the &lt;em&gt;public&lt;/em&gt; repository where I&amp;rsquo;m pushing the rendered site, I&amp;rsquo;m also tracking changes of the pure content and Hugo settings in a separate &lt;em&gt;private&lt;/em&gt; repository. I can safely say that once you understand the concept, it makes quite a lot of sense and is easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That would be it for the first post. I&amp;rsquo;m going to figure out how to use &lt;em&gt;menus&lt;/em&gt; and then add more pasts. Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
 </channel>
</rss>
